Guide to the Ship Scalers, Dry Dock, and Boat Yard Workers Union, Local 541 (Seattle, Washington) Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Ship Scalers, Dry Dock, and Boat Yard Workers Union, Local 541 (Seattle, Washington) Records, 1939-1991; 4571-001; 16 cubic feet 16 boxes
  - Series I: Constitution, Charter, Preamble and By-Laws, 1955-1986 (Box-folder 1/1-1/17)
    - Seattle Shipscalers Benevolent Corporation: Articles of Incorporation, Contracts, Invoices, Memoranda, Bank Statements, Bylaws, Elections, Minutes, 1956-1974 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Seattle Shipscalers Benevolent Corporation: Articles of Incorporation and Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1956-1979 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Seattle Shipscalers Benevolent Corporation: Articles of Incorporation and Correspondence with the Secretary of State's Office, 1956-1980 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Seattle Metal Trades Council: Amendment: Item 10, Article 11--"Dirty Work", 1958-1958 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Constitutions, Labor Law, Press: Tensions with Laborers' International Union of North America, 1972-1984 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Constitutions, Bylaws, Rules of Order, and Notes: International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Grant Proposal: "New Directions Program" Occupational Safety & Health Training; Union Constitution Booklet, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Contract Negotiations: Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council, 1982-1982 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Contract: Washington State Boat Builders and Associates, Inc. and Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council and the Seattle and Tacoma Metal Trades Councils, 1983-1983 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Constitution: Inlandboatmen's Union of the Pacific, 1985-1985 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Series II: Minutes, 1939-1986 (Box-folder 1/18-3/13)
    - Subseries A: Regular Membership Meeting Minutes, 1939-1986 (Box-folder 1/18-1/20)
      - Minutes: March 1939-December 1941, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 1/18)
      - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1979-1979 (Box-folder 1/19)
      - Hand-Written Meeting Minutes, 1986-1986 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Subseries B: International General Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 1/21)
      - Correspondence and Minutes: Special Meeting of the International Union General Executive Board, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Subseries C: Local Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1943-1982 (Box-folder 1/22-1/25)
      - Local Executive Board: Meeting Minutes, Case Against Rex Ricardo, Jr., Trial Board, Leaflets, and Insurance Documents, 1943-1966 (Box-folder 1/22)
      - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1954-1954 (Box-folder 1/23)
      - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 1/24)
      - Personal Minutes: Executive Board Meetings, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Subseries D: Combined Executive Board, Regular Membership Meeting, Special Meeting, and Benevolent Corporation Meeting Minutes, 1955-1986 (Box-folder 1/26-3/2)
      - Executive Board and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1955-1955 (Box-folder 1/26)
      - Executive Board and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1956-1956 (Box-folder 1/27)
      - Executive Board and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1956-1956 (Box-folder 1/28)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1957-1957 (Box-folder 1/29)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1957-1957 (Box-folder 1/30)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1958-1958 (Box-folder 1/31)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1958-1958 (Box-folder 1/32)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1959-1959 (Box-folder 1/33)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1959-1959 (Box-folder 1/34)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1960-1960 (Box-folder 1/35)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1960-1960 (Box-folder 1/36)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1961-1961 (Box-folder 1/37)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1961-1961 (Box-folder 2/1)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1962-1962 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1962-1962 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1963-1963 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1963-1963 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1964-1964 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1964-1964 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1965-1965 (Box-folder 2/8)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1965-1965 (Box-folder 2/9)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1966-1966 (Box-folder 2/10)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1966-1966 (Box-folder 2/11)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1967-1967 (Box-folder 2/12)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1967-1967 (Box-folder 2/13)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: January-June, 1968-1968 (Box-folder 2/14)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes: July-December, 1968-1968 (Box-folder 2/15)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1969-1969 (Box-folder 2/16)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1970-1970 (Box-folder 2/17)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1971-1971 (Box-folder 2/18)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1972-1972 (Box-folder 2/19)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1973-1973 (Box-folder 2/20)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1974-1974 (Box-folder 2/21)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1975-1975 (Box-folder 2/22)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 2/23)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1977-1977 (Box-folder 2/24)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 2/25)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 2/26)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1980-1980 (Box-folder 2/27)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 2/28)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1982-1982 (Box-folder 2/29)
      - Executive Board, Special, and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Meeting Minutes: General, Executive Board, Benevolent Corporation, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Subseries E: Membership, Repair and Safety Committees: Meeting Minutes, 1950-1974 (Box-folder 3/3-3/8)
      - Membership Committee Meeting Minutes, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Marine Construction and Repair Panel Committee Meeting Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 3/4)
      - Puget Sound Bridge and Dry Dock Company: Safety Committee Meeting Minutes, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 3/5)
      - Lake Union Dry Dock Company: Safety Committee Meeting Minutes, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 3/6)
      - Todd Shipyards Corporation: Labor-Management Safety Committee Meeting Minutes, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction Company: Plant Safety Committee Meeting Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Subseries F: Seattle Metal Trades Council Meeting Minutes, 1955-1985 (Box-folder 3/9-3/12)
      - Seattle Metal Trades Council: Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, and By-Laws, 1955-1980 (Box-folder 3/9)
      - Seattle Metal Trades Council Meeting Minutes, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 3/10)
      - Board of Trustees: Pacific Coast Shipyard Metal Trades Trust Fund: Meeting Minutes, 1967-1967 (Box-folder 3/11)
      - Metal Trades Council Special Meeting: Lockheed Shipbuilding Company Direct Misassignment of Work, 1985-1985 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Subseries G: Northwest Employees Retirement Fund Meeting Minutes, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 3/13)
      - Northwest Employees Retirement Plan Meeting Minutes, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Series III: Financial Records, 1946-1988 (Box-folder 3/14-3/23; 16/3; 3/24; 16/4; 3/25-3/31; 16/2; 3/32-3/37; 16/1; 3/38-3/42; 16/6; 3/43-4/57)
    - Subseries A: Internal Financial Records, 1946-1988 (Box-folder 3/14-3/23; 16/3; 3/24; 16/4; 3/25-3/31; 16/2; 3/32-3/37; 16/1; 3/38-3/42; 16/6; 3/43-4/24)
      - Financial Records, Press, and Correspondence, 1946-1987 (Box-folder 3/14)
      - Financial Records: Resolutions and Authorizations: Fiduciary Responsibility, 1955-1974 (Box-folder 3/15)
      - Financial Records: Seattle Shipscalers Benevolent Corporation, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 3/16)
      - Bylaws, Benevolent Association Incorporation Documents, Real Estate Contract, Bank Documents, 1956-1987 (Box-folder 3/17)
      - Financial Statements and Reports by John L. O'Brien and Company: Certified Public Accountants (1 of 2), 1958-1983 (Box-folder 3/18)
      - Financial Statements and Reports by John L. O'Brien and Company: Certified Public Accountants (2 of 2), 1958-1983 (Box-folder 3/19)
      - Financial Records: Internal Financial Management and Audits, 1962-1983 (Box-folder 3/20)
      - Financial: Statements, Correspondence, and Invoices, 1962-1986 (Box-folder 3/21)
      - Building Lease and Executive Board Correspondence, Insurance Claims, and Financial Documents, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - Seattle Shipscalers Benevolent Corporation: Documents Related to the Purchase of Building at 2311, 2313, and 2315 East Madison Street, Seattle, Washington, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - Ledger, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 16/3)
      - Strike at Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction Company; Deceased Members Lists; Financial Statements; Contract Negotiations, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 3/24)
      - Ledger, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 16/4)
      - Pay Rates, 1966-1980 (Box-folder 3/25)
      - Financial Records, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 3/26)
      - Executive Board Minutes; Forest E. Hilton Dues, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 3/27)
      - Dues Increases, 1968-1985 (Box-folder 3/28)
      - Non-Participation Struggle: International Union Pension Fund, 1968-1983 (Box-folder 3/29)
      - Correspondence Regarding Savings Account: Peoples National Bank of Washington, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 3/30)
      - Policy on Educational Conferences and Trustee Expense Voucher, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 3/31)
      - Ledger, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 16/2)
      - Financial Reports, 1972-1972 (Box-folder 3/32)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 3/33)
      - International Financial Report on Local 541, 1973-1973 (Box-folder 3/34)
      - International Financial Report on Local 541, 1973-1973 (Box-folder 3/35)
      - Transaction Registers, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 3/36)
      - Cash Balancing Report: Local 541, 1974-1974 (Box-folder 3/37)
      - Ledger, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 16/1)
      - Financial Statements: Retirement Fund; Legal Fees for Charter Revocation Services, 1974-1986 (Box-folder 3/38)
      - Dispatches to Lockheed Shipyard, 1975-1975 (Box-folder 3/39)
      - U.S. Department of Labor: Labor Organization Annual Report: Form LM-2, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 3/40)
      - Dispatches to Todd Shipyard (1 of 2), 1975-1977 (Box-folder 3/41)
      - Dispatches to Todd Shipyard (2 of 2), 1975-1977 (Box-folder 3/42)
      - Financial Report, 1975-1975 (Box-folder 16/6)
      - Financial Records, 1976-1988 (Box-folder 3/43)
      - Correspondence: Delinquent Members, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 3/44)
      - Records of Dispatches to Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 3/45)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 3/46)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, 1977-1977 (Box-folder 3/47)
      - Records of Dispatches to Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3/48)
      - Financial Statements: Receipts and Disbursements, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 3/49)
      - Sale of Property at 2313 East Madison in Seattle, WA, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 3/50)
      - Correspondence and Financial Statement: Northwest Employees Retirement Plan Trust Fund, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 3/51)
      - Ledger, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 3/52)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, 1978-1978 (Box-folder 3/53)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, 1979-1979 (Box-folder 3/54)
      - Checks to Edwina Fields from Local 541, 1979-1979 (Box-folder 3/55)
      - Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, Pay and Dues Records for Yvonne Quiroga, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 3/56)
      - Photocopies of Ledger, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 3/57)
      - Van T. Harrison: Correspondence with Fishing Vessels Owners and Duwamish Shipyard, Inc. Regarding Member Non-Payment of Dues, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 3/58)
      - Salary Information for International Officers, 1980-1980 (Box-folder 4/1)
      - Van T. Harrison: Correspondence with Employers Regarding Member Non-Payment of Dues, 1980-1980 (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Receipt for Rubber Stamp, 1980-1980 (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements: First and Second Quarter, 1980-1980 (Box-folder 4/4)
      - Monthly Reports of Income and Disbursements, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 4/5)
      - Letter to Oscar Hearde from Lustun House, et al Protesting Use of Local Funds for Personal Attorney Fees, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 4/6)
      - Correspondence, Petitions, and Press: Financial Responsibility for Oscar Hearde's Case Against the International, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 4/7)
      - Seattle First National Bank: Northwest Employees Retirement: Report No. SAV-414-1: Employees Monthly Composite Report (1 of 2), 1981-1981 (Box-folder 4/8)
      - Seattle First National Bank: Northwest Employees Retirement: Report No. SAV-414-1: Employees Monthly Composite Report (2 of 2), 1981-1981 (Box-folder 4/9)
      - Monthly Reports of Income and Disbursements, 1982-1982 (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Appeal of Fine by Kenneth Ponder: Taking Job Without Necessary Qualifications, 1982-1982 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Monthly Reports of Income and Disbursements, 1983-1983 (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Financial Records: Reports of Income and Disbursements, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Legal Bills: Gibbs and Associates, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 4/14)
      - Lien on Property at 2313 E. Madison in Seattle: Washington v. Shipscalers Local 541, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 4/15)
      - Monthly Reports of Income and Disbursements, 1984-1984 (Box-folder 4/16)
      - Monthly Reports of Income and Disbursements, 1985-1985 (Box-folder 4/17)
      - Financial Records: Debt Wrap-Up, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 4/18)
      - Financial Status Summary and Projected Financial Viability; Court Documents Regarding Dissolution Committee, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/19)
      - Monthly Reports of Income and Disbursements, 1986-1986 (Box-folder 4/20)
      - Union Dissolution: Bankruptcy, Debts, Building Sales, 1986-1986 (Box-folder 4/21)
      - Legal Invoice: Kenneth A. MacDonald, 1986-1986 (Box-folder 4/22)
      - Lien: Attorneys Fees: Law Firm of Gibbs, Douglas, Theiler and Drachler, 1986-1986 (Box-folder 4/23)
      - Legal and Financial Documents: Sale of Building at 2311 E. Madison Street in Seattle, WA, 1987-1987 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Subseries B: Tax Records, 1957-1986 (Box-folder 4/25-4/44)
      - Financial Records: Annual Reports to U.S. Department of Labor: Form LM-2, and Tax Exempt Status Form 990, 1957-1974 (Box-folder 4/25)
      - Department of Labor Tax Forms: 990, LM-2 and LM-3, 1957-1975 (Box-folder 4/26)
      - Tax Forms 990 and Department of Labor Forms LM-2, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 4/27)
      - Department of Labor: Labor Organization Annual Report: Form LM-2, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 4/28)
      - Wage Reporting/State Unemployment Taxes, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 4/29)
      - Employer's Quarterly Federal Tax Return: Form 941, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 4/30)
      - Employee W-2 Forms: Wage and Tax Statements, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 4/31)
      - Employer's Tax Report: S.F.5208 and Employer's Quarterly Report of Employee's Wages: S.F.5208-A, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 4/32)
      - Tax Forms 990 and Department of Labor Forms LM-2, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 4/33)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Reporting, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 4/34)
      - State of Washington Employment Security Department: Employer Quarterly Tax Report and Report of Employee's Wages, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 4/35)
      - Payroll Taxes: Employment Security Department, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 4/36)
      - Tax Forms: 990 and LM-2, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 4/37)
      - Tax Forms: 990 and LM-2, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 4/38)
      - Tax Forms: LM-2, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 4/39)
      - Tax Forms: 990 and LM-2, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4/40)
      - Tax Forms: 1096, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4/41)
      - State of Washington Employment Security Department: Employer Quarterly Tax Report and Report of Employee's Wages, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 4/42)
      - Tax Delinquency and Local Debts, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 4/43)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Reporting, 1984-1984 (Box-folder 4/44)
    - Subseries C: Audits, 1959-1985 (Box-folder 4/45-4/57)
      - Audit Reports, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 4/45)
      - Audit Reports, 1963-1963 (Box-folder 4/46)
      - Audit Reports, 1964-1964 (Box-folder 4/47)
      - Audit Reports, 1965-1965 (Box-folder 4/48)
      - Audit Report: Fourth Quarter, 1966-1966 (Box-folder 4/49)
      - Audit Reports, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4/50)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 4/51)
      - Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 4/52)
      - Correspondence from Joseph B. Warren and Charlie Cross to Lucious B. Jackson, Local President, Requesting Audit of Local Funds Due to Mismanagement by Business Manager/Secretary Treasurer, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 4/53)
      - Correspondence with Outside Labor Organizations; Local Audit, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 4/54)
      - Press, Leaflets, Correspondence, Notes, Contract Negotiations, Legal Documents, Safety Issues, Insurance Documents, Audit and Internal Accounting, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 4/55)
      - Local 541 Hearing Board: Charges Against Louise "Lou" Agtuca by Nancy D. San Carlos: Improper/Invalid Audit, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 4/56)
      - Northwest Employees Retirement Plan: Contribution Shortages; Press Regarding Shipscalers, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 4/57)
  - Series IV: Correspondence, 1939-1987 (Box-folder 4/58-5/37; 16/11-16/12; 5/38)
    - Subseries A: General Correspondence, 1939-1986 (Box-folder 4/58-5/6)
      - General Correspondence, 1939-1982 (Box-folder 4/58)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council, Press, Elections, Correspondence, Minutes, Legal Documents, 1951-1986 (Box-folder 4/59)
      - Reports, Correspondence, Minutes, Leaflets, and Legal Documents, 1960-1979 (Box-folder 4/60)
      - General Correspondence, 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4/61)
      - Correspondence and Union Office Administration Documents, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 4/62)
      - Field Notes: J.J. Hilton, 1971-1971 (Box-folder 5/1)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 5/2)
      - Correspondence, Arbitrations, Legal Documents and Research, Dues Increase, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Charges Against Theodore Edmondson Jr. by Christopher Tufts: Improper Discipline, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 5/4)
      - Restroom Memorandum: Polar Sea Vessel (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Contacts (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Subseries B: Local Officer Correspondence Files, 1951-1984 (Box-folder 5/7-5/15)
      - Secretary-Treasurer and Business Manager Donald T. Cameron: General Correspondence, 1951-1967 (Box-folder 5/7)
      - Secretary-Treasurer and Business Manager Donald T. Cameron: General Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - Secretary-Treasurer and Business Manager Donald T. Cameron: General Correspondence, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 5/9)
      - Secretary-Treasurer and Business Manager Donald T. Cameron: General Correspondence, 1965-1986 (Box-folder 5/10)
      - Masonic Correspondence: Letter to Past Most Worshipful Grand Master Lucious B. Jackson, 1980-1980 (Box-folder 5/11)
      - Correspondence: Joseph D. Warren, Business Manager, 1983-1983 (Box-folder 5/12)
      - Hand-Written Notes: Telephone Conversation About Member Issues: Bob Barnes, 1984-1984 (Box-folder 5/13)
      - Correspondence: Van T. Harrison and Pacific Fishermen, Inc., 1970-1980 (Box-folder 5/14)
      - Correspondence: Van T. Harrison and Todd Pacific Shipyard Corporation, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Subseries C: Correspondence: Financial and Contract Negotiation Administration, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 5/16-5/20)
      - Correspondence, Union Office Administration Documents, and Financial Documents, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 5/16)
      - Correspondence: Contract Negotiations: Washington State Boat Builders Metal Trades, 1977-1977 (Box-folder 5/17)
      - Correspondence: Special Meeting to Discuss Dues Increase, 1980-1980 (Box-folder 5/18)
      - Memoranda: Alternate Pay Criteria for Scalers, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 5/19)
      - Correspondence: Pension Rights Center, 1983-1983 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Subseries D: Correspondence With and Regarding the Laborers International Union of North America, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 5/21-5/26)
      - Leaflets to Membership: Elections, Work Conditions, Dissolution Committee, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 5/21)
      - Correspondence: Rank-and-File Challenge of International Union Leaders, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 5/22)
      - Victor Kamber: Report on Union Democratization: Sent to Ann Zill to Discourage Grant Funding, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 5/23)
      - Correspondence: Public Citizen Litigation Group: Laborers International Union of North America Constitutional Amendments, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 5/24)
      - Letter to International President Angelo Fosco from Membership of Local 541: Response to Suspension, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 5/25)
      - Correspondence between Oscar Hearde and the Senate Subcommittee on Investigations Regarding International Union Officers and Organized Crime, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Subseries E: Internal Tensions, 1963-1986 (Box-folder 5/27-5/37)
      - Local Trial Board: Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 5/27)
      - Correspondence, Statements of Charges, Legal Documents: Local 541 v. Van T. Harrison, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 5/28)
      - Correspondence to General Membership from Bob Barnes and Oscar Hearde, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 5/29)
      - Correspondence: Secretary-Treasurer Robert A. Barnes: Internal Tensions, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 5/30)
      - Interpersonal Issue Between Grace Sifres and Anna Castro: Notes and Correspondence, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 5/31)
      - Disciplinary Action After Sign-Up Problems: Robert Chaney, Larry Pritchard, Karen Smith, Isaac Williams, 1981-1981 (Box-folder 5/32)
      - Letter to Oscar Hearde from Mary Bingham: Harassment Charges Against Foreman Ted Edmondson, 1982-1982 (Box-folder 5/33)
      - Notes and Correspondence: Executive Board Charges Against Theodore Edmondson Jr., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 5/34)
      - Correspondence: Trial Board Hearing on Ted Edmondson Charges, 1984-1984 (Box-folder 5/35)